[{
        "question": "The break statement in Java is used to ___.",
        "options": [
            "Terminates from the loop immediately",
            "Terminates from the program immediately",
            "Skips the current iteration",
            "All of these"
        ],
        "answer": "Terminates from the loop immediately",
        "explanation": "The break statement in Java is used to terminate from the loop immediately."
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of following Java code?\n\npublic class Main {\n  public static void main(String arg[]) {\n    int i;\n    for (i = 1; i <= 12; i += 2) {\n      if (i == 8) {\n        System.out.println(i);\n        break;\n      }\n    }\n  }\n}",
        "options": ["1", "No output", "8", "1357911"],
        "answer": "No output",
        "explanation": "The condition (i == 8) could not be satisfied hence nothing cannot be printed."
    },
    {
        "question": "Can the Java program accept input from the command line?",
        "options": [
            "Yes, using command-line arguments",
            "Yes, by access command prompt",
            "No",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "answer": "Yes, using command-line arguments",
        "explanation": "In Java, we can also provide values (arguments) while calling the program through the command line. These arguments are known as Command Line Arguments."
    },
    {
        "question": "Array in java is ___.",
        "options": [
            "Collection of similar elements",
            "Collection of elements of different types",
            "The data type of consisting of characters",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "answer": "Collection of similar elements",
        "explanation": "Array is a collection of similar elements."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is the correct method to create an array in java?",
        "options": [
            "int[] arr = {1, 3, 5};",
            "int[] arr;\narr = new int[] {3, 1, 8};",
            "int arr[] = {1, 4, 6};",
            "All of these"
        ],
        "answer": "All of these",
        "explanation": "Read here: How to declare and initialize an array in Java?"
    },
    {
        "question": "Object in java are ___.",
        "options": ["Classes", "References", "Iterators", "None of these"],
        "answer": "References",
        "explanation": "Objects in Java are Reference Variables."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is garbage collection in java?",
        "options": [
            "Method to manage memory in java",
            "Create new garbage values",
            "Delete all values",
            "All of these"
        ],
        "answer": "Method to manage memory in java",
        "explanation": "Garbage collection in Java is the process by which Java programs perform automatic memory management."
    },
    {
        "question": "Static variables in java are declared as ___.",
        "options": ["final variables", "new variables", "Constants", "All of these"],
        "answer": "Constants",
        "explanation": "The static variables declarations just like constants, they required static keyword and an initial value."
    },
    {
        "question": "BigInteger Class is used to ___.",
        "options": [
            "Store very long range of number",
            "Store integer values",
            "A class that stores large range of integer",
            "All of these"
        ],
        "answer": "All of these",
        "explanation": "All of the above points are correct with respect to a BigInteger class."
    },
    {
        "question": "'this' keyword in java is ___.",
        "options": [
            "Used to hold the reference of the current object",
            "Holds object value",
            "Used to create a new instance",
            "All of these"
        ],
        "answer": "Used to hold the reference of the current object",
        "explanation": "Java 'this' keyword is used to hold the reference of the current object."
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of following Java code?\n\nimport java.util.Scanner;\n\nclass ThisKeyword {\n  private int a = 4;\n  private int b = 1;\n\n  void getSum(int a, int b) {\n    this.a = a;\n    this.b = b;\n    System.out.println(this.a + this.b);\n  }\n}\n\npublic class Main {\n  public static void main(String args[]) {\n    ThisKeyword T = new ThisKeyword();\n    T.getSum(3, 5);\n  }\n}",
        "options": ["5", "9", "8", "4"],
        "answer": "8",
        "explanation": "The above Java program is an example to demonstrate the use of this keyword."
    },
    {
        "question": "The 'super' keyword is used to ___.",
        "options": [
            "Access instance of the parent class",
            "Access instance of the same class",
            "Access instance of child class",
            "Access instance of friend class"
        ],
        "answer": "Access instance of the parent class",
        "explanation": "The super keyword refers to superclass (parent) objects. It is used to call superclass methods, and to access the superclass constructor."
    },
    {
        "question": "The super() method is used to ___.",
        "options": [
            "Call constructor of friend class",
            "Is a declared method",
            "Call constructor of the parent class",
            "Call constructor"
        ],
        "answer": "Call constructor of the parent class",
        "explanation": "In Java programming language, the super() is a reference variable that is used to refer parent class constructors. The super can be used to call parent class's variables and methods. The super() can be used to call parent class' constructors only."
    },
    {
        "question": "Wrapper class in java is ___.",
        "options": [
            "Used to encapsulate primitive data types",
            "Declare new classes called wrapper",
            "Create a new instance of the class",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "answer": "Used to encapsulate primitive data types",
        "explanation": "A Wrapper class is a class whose object wraps or contains primitive data types."
    },
    {
        "question": "Boxing is ___.",
        "options": [
            "Creating new box",
            "Creating object",
            "Converting primitive type of object instance",
            "All of these"
        ],
        "answer": "Converting primitive type of object instance",
        "explanation": "In Java programming language, the wrapper classes are those whose objects wraps a primitive data type within them. The wrapper class is used for converting primitive datatype to object is called boxing."
    },
    {
        "question": "Abstract class is ___.",
        "options": [
            "Created using abstract keyword",
            "Contains only abstract method",
            "Needs to be inherited to be used",
            "All of these"
        ],
        "answer": "All of these",
        "explanation": "An abstract class is a class that contains an abstract method. It is defined using abstract keyword only has method declarations and to use these methods, the abstract class needs to be inherited."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is file handling in java?",
        "options": [
            "It is creating, deleting, and modifying files using a java program.",
            "Creating new method",
            "Filing method to different file to extract them better",
            "All of these"
        ],
        "answer": "It is creating, deleting, and modifying files using a java program.",
        "explanation": "File handling is used for creating, deleting, and modifying files using a java program."
    },
    {
        "question": "How can we access methods for file handling in java?",
        "options": [
            "Java.files",
            "Java.io",
            "Java.io.File",
            "Java.FileHandling"
        ],
        "answer": "Java.io.File",
        "explanation": "To access the file handling methods, we need to use Java.io.File."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the correct absolute path of a file in Java?",
        "options": [
            "C:\\Program Files\\Java\\jdk1.8.0_131\\bin\\file_name.txt",
            "C:\\Program Files\\Java\\file_name.txt",
            "C:\\Program Files\\Java\\jdk1.8.0_131\\file_name.txt",
            "C:\\Program Files\\Java\\jdk1.8.0_131\\bin\\File Handling\\file_name.txt"
        ],
        "answer": "C:\\Program Files\\Java\\jdk1.8.0_131\\bin\\file_name.txt",
        "explanation": "The correct absolute path of a file in Java is:\n\nC:\\Program Files\\Java\\jdk1.8.0_131\\bin\\file_name.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which method is used to add a new line to file in Java?",
        "options": ["file.addLine()", "file.nextLine()", "file.write()", "file.line()"],
        "answer": "file.write()",
        "explanation": "The file.write() method is used to add a new line to file in Java."
    }
]